vervante.com 2018-10-12

# Privacy Policy

Your privacy is very important. Here are a few fundamental principles that we follow:

  * We don't ask you for personal information unless we truly need it. 

  * We don't share your personal information with anyone except to comply with the law, develop our products, or protect our rights.

  * We don't store personal information our servers unless required for the on-going operation of our site.

##  What personal data we collect and why we collect it:

###  Order Processing

When you order, we need to know your name, e-mail address, mailing address, credit card number, and credit card expiration date. This allows us to process and fulfill your order and to notify you of your order status.

Vervante uses the latest encryption technology to keep your personal information safe. All your ordering information -- including your name, address, and credit card number -- is encrypted using a secure server for maximum security.

Credit card transactions are handled by a third-party financial institution, which receives the credit card number and other personal identifying information only to verify the credit card numbers and process transactions.

###  Opt-in forms

This site uses opt-in forms to collect your name and email for marketing purposes so we can notify you about related content and special offers. Submissions are kept indefinitely. If you submit an opt-in form on our site you will be opting in for us to save your name, email address and other relevant information. You can opt out or unsubscribe at any time in the future by clicking the unsubscribe link in the bottom of any email.

### Analytics

This site uses Google Analytics to see how visitors find and use our website.

##  Who we share your data with:

Vervante does not sell or rent our customers' personal information (including customers' names and shipping, billing, and e-mail addresses) to anyone. Vervante may release account information when we believe, in good faith, that such release is reasonably necessary to (i.) comply with law, (ii.) enforce or apply the terms of any of our user agreements, or (iii.) protect the rights, property, or safety of Vervante, our users, or others.

All personal information collected on contact or opt-in forms is shared with MailChimp and their privacy policy can be viewed here: [https://mailchimp.com/legal/privacy/](https://mailchimp.com/legal/privacy/).

##  How long we retain your data:

For users that register on our website (if any), we also store the personal information they provide in their user profile. All users can see, edit, or delete their personal information at any time (except they cannot change their username). Website administrators can also see and edit that information.

Subscriber information is retained in the local database indefinitely for analytic tracking purposes and for future export. Data will be exported or removed upon users request. Data is retained in MailChimp until unsubscribed or deleted and will be removed upon users request.

##  What rights you have over your data:

If you have an account on this site or filled out an opt-in form you can request to receive an exported file of the personal data we hold about you, including any data you have provided to us. You can also request that we erase any personal data we hold about you. This does not include any data we are obliged to keep for administrative, legal, or security purposes.

##  Privacy Policy Changes

Although most changes are likely to be minor, we may change the privacy policy from time to time, and at our sole discretion. Visitors are encouraged to frequently check our Terms & Conditions for any changes to its Privacy Policy. Your continued use of this site after any change in this Privacy Policy will constitute your acceptance of such change.

By using our web site, you consent to the collection and use of your information by Vervante. If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes on this page so that you are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances we disclose it.
